廁 零 手 位
所 食 機 置
先 備 關 坐
上 妥 掉 定
華納兄弟影業公司
時代華納企業
特　效　　　　卓　著
WJ-MAFIA
I'm going to tell you a story
我要給你講一個故事
about a boy who would never grow up,
關於一個男孩
他永遠都不會長大
about the pirate who wished to kill him,
關於一個海盜
一心想殺掉這個男孩
about the island where fairies roamed.
關於一個島嶼
上面住滿了精靈
But this isn't the story you've heard before,
但這不是一個你以前聽說過的那個故事
because sometimes...
因為有時候…
friends begin as enemies,
敵人會變成朋友
and enemies begin as friends.
朋友也會變成敵人
Sometimes to truly understand how things end,
如果想真正知道故事是怎麼結束的
we must first know how they begin.
就要從故事的最開始說起
Come on.
來吧
關閉
肯辛頓王宮花園
永恆修女之家
朗伯斯孤兒院
彼得
I love you, my son.
親愛的，兒子
I love you,
我愛你
my Peter.
我的彼得
小飛俠
幻夢啟航
Wakey, wakey!
起床了！
Rise and shine!
都日上三竿了！
Come on, now.
來吧
That's it. Come on.
這就對了，過來
Move along. Come on, quickly now.
往這邊
快點
十二年後
倫敦，第二次世界大戰
Peter, we'll miss breakfast.
彼得，我們快趕不上早飯了
The heroes have risen.   They must now feed!
小英雄們已經起床了
他們現在就需要進餐！
Quiet over there!
你們給我安靜點！
I said quiet!
我說安靜點！
Eat that up! Now.
快吃飯！
I won't tell you again!
我不會再重複一遍了！
Where's the bacon?
培根在哪裡？
We always have bacon rind of a weekend.
我們週末總是有培根皮的
There's a war on, Peter. Rationing.
彼得，現在在打仗
東西都有配額的
You're lucky to have any food at all.
你有吃的就很不錯了
- Oh! Mother Barnabas, forgive me.     - Get over there.
-芭芭拉修女，請您原諒  -別擋路
How much you wanna bet she's nickin' all the rations?
你想賭多少錢？  她把所有配額都偷了
Shh. She'll hear ya.
她會聽見你說話的
She's got ears like an elephant.
她耳朵簡直和大象那麼大
Bum like one, too.
屁股也像大象一樣
Look.
看
More empty seats.
有空位
Nelson and Billy both got evacuated.
尼爾森和比利都被撤離了
Lucky sods.
那幫幸運的混球
Both of them?
兩個都走了？
- When?     - Don't know.
-什麼時候走的？  -不清楚
When I woke up, they were both gone.
我一覺醒來，他倆都沒影了
Off to some family in Canada until the war's over.
他們應該會和他們加拿大的家人
一起住到戰爭結束
I wouldn't mind goin' there.
我要是也能去就好了
Don't be daft. You gotta stay put.
別做夢了，你得和我一起留在這裡
For when our mums come fetch us?
我們的媽媽什麼時候會過來？
Exactly.
不知道
We hunker down here. Hold the fort.
我們躲在這裡很安全
Wait for the cavalry.
等騎兵來吧
Now, get on that roof and clean those filthy gutters.
去房頂把那些髒東西搞乾淨
Is it safe, Mother Barnabas?
芭芭拉修女，那樣安全嗎？
Well, I've not tested it meself, like.
我又沒做過，我怎麼知道
You know, not recently.
起碼最近沒做過
But all the necessary paperwork is in order
如果孤兒不幸摔下死亡
should an orphan perish in a fall.
反正文件是準備好了
Now get up there!
上房頂吧！
And while you're aloft and closer to our Lord,
你在那麼高的地方離上帝也近一點
you may reflect on your festering souls.
他也能看到你那腐爛的靈魂
Your souls that fester as do the leaves.
你的靈魂就像那些爛葉子一樣
See! I was right!
看！我就說！
She's hoarding all the rations.
她把所有的配額都藏起來了！
Where's she hiding all the grub?
她把食物都藏哪裡了？
Her office. No one's ever been in there.
她的辦公室
沒人去那個地方
I heard a rumor it's booby trapped.
我還聽說她在那裡放了很多機關
Silence, I said! Quiet!
安靜！我說，安靜！
Everyone, down to the shelters!
所有人到防空洞裡來！
In chaos is death!
發出聲音你就會害死所有人！
- Come on.     - I don't like this.
-過來  -我不喜歡這裡
Fort Knox.
諾克斯堡
The lair of the dragon.
龍潭虎穴
Come here.
過來
So put your hands there.
把你手放到這裡
咨詢辦公室
I need your shoe, fella.
夥計，把你的鞋子給我
- Could you just...     - Quiet!
-你能不能…  -安靜！
Right.
好吧
Nineteen.
十九
Twenty.
二十
Peter.
彼得
Ugh. What a dirty old nun.
那個骯髒的老修女
Ugh.
惡！
This is so unhygienic.
這裡太髒了
Why is the Virgin Mary so clean?
這個聖母瑪利亞為什麼乾淨？
- Nibs?     - Down here!
-尼布斯？  -下來
Nibsy!
尼布斯！
I told ya.
我早告訴你了
Booby trapped.
有圈套
It's a treasure trove.
這是個藏寶室
Flippin' heck!
老天！
Peter!
彼得！
It's the records.
是孤兒們的檔案
Peter!
彼得！
It's your file.
這是你的檔案
朗伯斯孤兒院文檔
彼得
我最親愛的彼得
Is it from your mum?
是你媽媽寫的嗎？
我你愛……我回來會
What does she say?
她說什麼？
I can't.
我無法讀
Will you read it?
你能讀嗎？
- I meant aloud.     - Oh.
-讀出聲  -好
"My dearest Peter.
我最親愛的彼得
"Everything I have done,
「我所做的一切…
I have done because I love you.
「我所做的一切都是因為我愛你」
"I long for the day that I can come back for you
「我期待著回到你身邊的那一天」
"and explain everything.
「我會向你解釋」
"Don't doubt me
「要相信我」
"nor most importantly,
「最重要的是」
don't doubt yourself.
「相信你自己」
"You are extraordinary."
「你是個非凡的孩子」
"More than you can imagine."
「你比你想像的還厲害」
I promise that you will see me again,
「我向你保證我們會再見面的」
in this world or another.
「不管在這個世界還是在另一個」
Come on!
快走！
彼 得
That's my private property!   Give it back!
這是我的私人物品！  還給我！
You know, Peter, every little orphan dreams he's special.
你知道，彼得
所有孤兒都覺得他是最特殊的
That he'll be the one...
他是被選中的那一個
whose mother comes a-skipping back for him.
他媽媽會回來接他
But your mammy's not for skipping.
但你媽媽不會回來的
And why is that, hmm?
你知道為什麼嗎？
Because you're not special, Peter.
彼得，因為你沒什麼特別的
You're not even special
你和你的同伴們
in your own way.
一點區別都沒有
You're just a nasty little creature
你只不過是個惹人討厭的小東西
abandoned by a feckless mammy
被你無用的母親拋棄
who's forgotten you exist.
她早就把你忘了
Oh! You little savage!
你這個野種！
Hands! The both of ya!
把手伸出來！你們兩個！
He never did nothin'!
他什麼都沒做！
He's guilty by association.
他是同黨
It is time for the pine.
是時候…上戒尺了
Oi, Skinny.
嘿，豆芽菜
Arnold and the twins, when did they go?
阿諾德和雙胞胎去哪裡了？
Me guess it were last night.
他們可能昨晚走了
All the missing children,
所有消失的兒童
all that dough hidden in her office.
還有她藏在她辦公室裡的東西
What's Barnabas up to?
芭芭拉到底在做什麼？
She's selling orphans.
她在賣孤兒
I knew it!
我早就知道！
I mean, is she? That's not nice.
是嗎？她可真差勁
But who in the world buys orphans at night?
但是誰會買孤兒呢？
That's what we have to find out.
我們會找出來的
Now, come on, let's make a plan. It'll be fun.
來吧，我們定個計劃
這會很有趣的
I've heard that one before.
上一次你也這麼說
Cor! Who guffed one?
天啊！誰放屁了！
Nibsy!
尼布斯！
I never.
不是我
Mmm-mmm. Mmm-mmm.
高一點！
This was a stupid plan.   I'm going back to bed.
這是個蠢計劃
我要回去睡覺了
Come on.
走吧
- Night.     - Night.
-晚安  -晚安
- Nibs!     - Peter!
-尼布斯！  -彼得！
I told you it would happen tonight.
我告訴你了今晚就會發生
I was right!
我早就知道！
What?
什麼？
Head for the stairs.
往樓梯那裡跑！
Go!
走！
Nibs!
尼布斯！
Goodbye, Peter!
再見，彼得！
- You're comin' with me!     - Let go!
-我也要帶你走！  -放開我！
Peter.
彼得
Holy pudding!
老天爺！
Prepare to set sail!
準備啟程！
We've gotta get out of here.
我們必須離開這裡
We'll have to jump.
我們必須跳下去
I can't!
我不行！
We have to!
我們必須跳！
Come on!
快點！
Nibs!
尼布斯！
And away we go!
跳吧！
Come on!
快點！
Friends till death!
我們到死都是朋友！
Peter!
彼得！
注意：空軍駐扎
Damnation. You've sunk my frigate.
混蛋
你搞沉了我的護衛艦
Ma'am. Luftwaffe. Inbound.
長官，納粹空軍正在逼近
Ladies.
女士們
Sector 6, sector 8, sector 12.
6區、8區、12區
Incoming!
來了！
Spitfire!
開火了！
- Clear the deck!     - Ready your swords!
-所有人到甲板底下！  -準備好武器！
Oh, come on!
快點！
Ma'am, regarding identification of the enemy, um, aircraft,
長官，關於敵方飛機的身份
it rather resembles a, um...
它看起來像是…
Spit it out, man.
說吧
It looks like a pirate ship, ma'am.
看起來像是海盜船，長官
Come again?
什麼？
Fire!
開火！
Get off.
滾開
Don't go dying.
別作死
You're precious cargo.
你可是值錢貨
- Am I?     - Somebody thinks so.
-我？  -反正有人這麼覺得
Is it my mother?
是我媽媽嗎？
Going up!
升空！
Get out here! You little rat!
滾出去，你這個小混球！
Make your move!
該你了！
Come on, hurry up!
快點！
Move it! Come on!
- Right this ship for docking.     - Haul away!
-船要靠岸了  -拉繩子！
Come on, fellas.
夥計們，加把勁
Look! It's daylight.
看！天亮了
I wanna see this!
我想看看
- What is that?     - Move, I can't see.
-這是什麼？  -別擋著我，我看不見
□ Hello, hello, hello, how low? □
□ 哈羅，哈羅，哈羅，多低劣 □
Is this Canada?
這是加拿大嗎？
□ Turn the lights out.   It's less dangerous. □
□ 關掉燈光，少險惡 □
□ Here we are now.   Entertain us. □
□ 我們在這，自娛自樂 □
□ I feel stupid.   And contagious. □
□ 愚蠢逐漸，蔓延開來 □
□ Here we are now.   Entertain us. □
□ 我們在這，自娛自樂 □
□ Hey! □
□ 嘿！ □
□ Hello, hello, hello, how low? □
□ 哈羅，哈羅，哈羅，多低劣 □
Sing!
一起唱！
□ Hello, hello, hello, how low? □
□ 哈羅，哈羅，哈羅，多低劣 □
Kneel!
跪下！
I don't kneel to anyone.
我不向任何人下跪
Oh, you'll kneel to him.
但你需要向他下跪
He's the pirate all pirates fear!
他是海盜之王！
The original nightmare!
噩夢的開始！
The man they call Blackbeard!
他就是黑鬍子！
□ And I forget just why I taste. □
□ 我忘記了我為何嘗試 □
□ Oh, yeah, I guess it makes me smile. □
□ 對了，我猜是因為那讓我高興 □
□ I found it hard, so hard to find. □
□ 我發現找到笑容是那麼那麼的困難 □
□ Oh, well, whatever, never mind. □
□ 不過，無論如何，心態放自然 □
□ Hello, hello, hello, how low? □
□ 哈羅，哈羅，哈羅，多低劣 □
□ With the lights out.   It's less dangerous. □
□ 燈光熄滅，少險惡 □
□ Here we are now.   Entertain us. □
□ 我們在這，自娛自樂 □
□ I feel stupid and contagious. □
□ 愚蠢逐漸，蔓延開了 □
Sing for your master!
為你的主人高歌吧！
□ Here we are now.   Entertain us. □
□ 我們在這，自娛自樂 □
Sweet, gentle children.
我親愛的孩子們
You who weep molten pearls of innocent tears,
不要再流下你們珍珠般的、天真的眼淚
dry them, dear nippers.
孩子們，擦乾眼淚
For I have sprung you from life's cruel dungeon,
因為我已經把你們從那個地牢裡救了出來
and hereby grant you liberty!
給你們自由了！
Suffer no more.
你們的痛苦結束了
Come unto me. You are home.
來吧，你們到家了
Here you join orphans alike from every corner of the globe,
你會找到其他的孤兒，從世界各個角落來
every race, creed, and color.
不同民族、信仰
Every age and era.
不同年齡與時代
You are pioneers.
你們是先驅者
Brave creators of a new society.
新社會的建造者
For this, my poppets, is a land of opportunity!
正因如此，孩子們，這裡就是新大陸！
My justice is divine.
我就是最高法律
My laws are so simple you could write them on a pig's ear.
我的法律很簡單，簡單到可以寫到豬耳朵上
In fact, I have.
我也的確寫上去了
Law number one,
第一條
"Those who work with bright, honest vigor will be rewarded with prizes
「努力誠實工作的人，會得到獎勵」
"and trophies
「和獎盃」
"and confectionery!"
「還有糖果！」
Law number two,
第二條
"Those who fail to work hard,
「不努力工作的人」
"those who skive or malinger,
「裝病扯謊的人」
"will hereby know the brooding majesty of my disapproval."
「將會被本大王厭棄」
Mark me well.
我說到做到
I know no pity.
我不同情任何人
No second chances. I don't do mercy.
沒有第二次機會，我不憐憫任何人
But remember,
但是記住
don't forget to help yourselves
別忘了讓你們自己…
to lots and lots of jolly old fun!
痛痛快快地玩耍！
Hey, kiddiewinks,
孩子們
welcome to Neverland!
歡迎來到夢幻島！
Put some effort into it.
要努力工作
You better find me some Pixum!
給我找點精靈粉！
Harder! Work harder!
努力！再努力一點工作！
Uh, Sam Smiegel, supervisor.
山姆史密戈，監工
No, thank you. Take it off.
不用了，謝謝
把它拿下來吧
- Whoa!     - Excuse me.
-噢！  -不好意思
What are we digging for?
我們在挖什麼？
Did no one explain?
沒人跟你解釋？
We are mining
我們在挖
for these little chaps.
這些精靈粉
Fairy dust, otherwise known as Pixum.
精靈粉塵
也叫精靈粉
Fairies are real?
精靈是真的？
Mmm. They were real, yeah.
曾經是真的
There were millions of them all over the island.
這島上曾經有幾百萬精靈
What happened to 'em?
他們怎麼了？
Oh, Blackbeard hunted them into extinction.
黑鬍子把他們殺光了
- Why?     - For the fairy dust.
-為什麼？  -為了這些精靈粉
You know, the old Pixum.
你知道，為了精靈粉
What does he want it for?
他要那些做什麼？
I don't have no idea.
我不知道
No one knows. No one's allowed to know.
誰都不知道
他也不讓其他人知道
Well, you best not dwell on it. Just...
別想那麼多，不過…
Get a move on!
繼續工作！
Real, actual fairies.
精靈是真的
Hey, new kid,
喂，新來的
you just got here on a flying pirate ship.
你剛剛從一個能飛的海盜船下來
"Real" should be a very fluid concept for you right now.
「真精靈」這個概念你應該不難接受
Get to diggin'.
繼續挖吧
Give me your pick, kid.
把你的鎯頭給我
Your hand's all messed up because your blade is blunted.
你的鎯頭都鈍了，所以你的手都磨破了
If you keep swingin' like that,
如果你還這樣揮它
you're gonna break your wrist.
你會傷到你自己的手腕
I'm Peter.
我叫彼得
How long have you been here?
你在這裡多久了？
Forever.
很久了
Do you know why they want it so badly? The Pixum?
你知道他們為什麼這麼想要精靈粉嗎？
You ask too many questions, kid.
孩子，你話太多了
They kill for it.   We die for it. End of story.
他們無論如何都要得到這些精靈粉
就這樣
- Thanks very much.     - Don't thank me.
-謝謝  -別謝我
I don't care about you.
我不在乎你
I'm not your friend,
我不是你的朋友
and I haven't got your back.
我也不會保護你
Simple as that.
懂了嗎？
Shoo, kid.
走開吧，小子
Fairy dust.
精靈粉
I found some.
我找到了一些
That's mine!
那是我的！
No!
不是！
I found some!
我找到了！
Oi, thief! I found it!
小偷！是我找到的！
Oi, small fry, button it.
閉嘴，小子
Move!
讓開！
Give it to me.
把它給我
It was me! I found the fairy Pixum!
是我！  是我找到的精靈粉！
This bogey stole it.
這個混蛋偷了我的！
He said he found it.
他說是他找到的
That means he found it. Clear?
所以就是他找到的
清楚了嗎？
Clear as the scar on your ugly face!
就像看你這個刀疤臉一樣清楚
Take him to the Captain!
把他帶到船長那裡！
Disorder and verbals.
不守紀律，還頂嘴
Move out of the way. Move it.
讓開，都讓開
Get out of the way!
全都給我讓開！
There... There is a procedure for this, you know.
你們知道這種情況是有處理規章的
You're not supposed to...
你們不應該…
- Shut it, Mr. Clipboard.     - Oh!
-閉嘴，砧板先生  -噢！
Let's see what Blackbeard makes of this nasty little thief.
我們來看看黑鬍子將會如何審判，這個令人厭惡的小偷
Oh, what you lookin' at?   I was tryin' my best.
你看什麼？  我已經盡力了
Well, go on, then.   Back to work. Thank you.
好了，都回去工作吧
謝謝
Did you find the natives' camp?
找到土著人的營地了嗎？
They found us, sir.
他們找到了我們，先生
They sprang from the trees and laid waste to 40 of our most formidable men.
他們從樹上跳下來，殺掉了我們中最勇敢的40人
Then they disappeared back into the forest as if they were never there.
然後就消失了，他們重新跑到了森林裡，然後再也沒找到他們
We will get them, Captain.
我們會找到他們的，船長
Given the proper time.
我們需要等一段時間
Time?
時間？
Mmm.
嗯
I have sucked these mines dry.
這些精靈粉礦都枯竭了
There's almost nothing left.   I must have their lands.
什麼都沒有了，我需要他們的地盤
But these savages
但是這些野人
continue to ambush my ships,
一直在打我艦隊的埋伏
operating from some hidden camp,
從隱蔽的地方突襲
which no one can seem to find.
誰都找不到他們
And yet you assure me all will be well given the proper time.
你卻在這裡打包票，只要給你時間你就找得到他們
There is no time! None!
已經沒時間了！沒了！
Excuse me, Captain.
不好意思，船長
Hey ho.
嗯
The show must go on.
日子總要過下去
How do the miners seem?
最近礦工們怎麼樣？
Dirty, feverish, on the brink of collapse, sir.
又髒又累
都快崩潰了
Why must it be so hard?
達到目標就這麼難嗎？
So...
這樣
Who are we making an example of today?
今天我們需要殺哪隻雞來儆猴？
□ Hey ho, let's go! □
□ They're forming in a straight line □
□ They're going through a tight wind □
No, no!
不！
What's going on?
發生了什麼？
What do you think?
你覺得呢？
□ They're piling in the backseat □
□ They're generating steam heat □
□ Pulsating to the backbeat □
□ The Blitzkrieg Bop □
Any clearer now?
你懂現在是什麼情況嗎？
□ Hey ho, let's go! □
Yeah!
哈
Brave heroes of Neverland,
夢幻島的英雄們！
behold these traitors.
看看這些叛徒
I entrust their fate to your gracious whim.
他們的命運將由你們來決定
This barbarian...
這個野種
...caught stealing from the grain store.
在糧店偷東西時被人抓到
...was caught squealing from the grain store.
尖叫時被人抓到
Stealing.
偷東西時
- Stealing.     - Twice.
-偷東西時  -兩次
Twice!
兩次！
- Will you spare him?     - No!
-你們能放過他嗎？  -不可以！
Or do you lust for justice?
我們要用正義懲罰他嗎？
Justice!
正義！
- Yes!     - Justice!
-對！  -正義！
- Do they ever have mercy?     - Oh, yes. They do.
-他們讓人活過嗎？  -有過
Often?
經常嗎？
Uh...
呃…
Let's go!
走吧！
Don't answer that.
我可不想這樣
This boy has been in our mines but one day
這個孩子只在我們的礦山一天
and has already proven himself to be a thief,
就被發現是個小偷
a rabble rouser, and a Pixum fraudster.
真是個害群之馬，還偷精靈粉
- I never!     - I ask,
-我沒有！  -我問大家
shall you have mercy for the willful child?
對這個孩子需要仁慈嗎？
No!
不需要！
Or do ye be nasty?
還是你們想看點刺激的？
Nasty!
來刺激的！
Nasty! Nasty! Nasty!
刺激的！
Alack.
抱歉
The people have spoken.
群眾已經表態了
Think a happy thought.
想點高興事
I'll be darned.
我的老天
I don't believe it! I can fly!
我簡直不能相信！我會飛了！
Neverland is a dream...
夢幻島是個夢
from which you never wake.
你永遠無法從夢中醒來
Ever had that one?
你做過那樣的夢嗎？
A dreadful nightmare you know is not real,
不過是個噩夢罷了
又不是真的
but your sleep is so heavy,
但是你睡得太沉了
so deep, so delicious
深沉的美夢
that you just can't wake up.
你總是醒不過來
Drowning in sleep.
沉迷在夢中
Slow dream
一個緩慢的夢境
drowning in the soft, black sea.
在柔軟的黑色海洋裡沉淪
Do you know that sea, Peter?
你知道那片海嗎，彼得？
It's death, boy.
那就是死亡，小子
Murmuring to you.
在對你低語
It's where we end.
那就是我們的終點
Most of us.
或大多數人的
Would you like some chocolate?
你想來點巧克力嗎？
Childhood ain't so jolly.
並不愉快的童年
In fact, it's rather frightening.
事實上，週遭環境也很可怕
Agree?
是嗎？
Are you brave, Peter?
彼得，你是個勇敢的孩子嗎？
I try to be.
我試著做個那樣的人
Yes, of course.
當然
Are you scared?
你怕了嗎？
Yes.
是
Have you ever flown before?
你以前飛過嗎？
No.
沒有
Beyond that wall, there are savage people.
在那堵牆之外，都是些野人
They have an ancient prophecy
他們有個古老的預言
from when the fairy kingdoms reigned on this island.
從精靈們統治這塊地時就有了
The prophecy tells of a boy born of the love
預言說這個男孩因愛而生
between a fairy prince and a human girl.
父親是精靈王子
母親是人類女孩
A boy who would be disappeared from this world
這孩子會從這世界消失
until he was old enough to return and lead an uprising against me.
當他到了年齡時，就會回來，帶領叛軍來反抗我
A boy, so says the prophecy,
這個男孩，在預言裡
who could fly.
可以飛
Have you come to kill me, Peter?
你是來殺我的嗎，彼得？
I don't believe in bedtime stories.
我不信這些童話故事
會見到我…
還是另一個…
"Me... Me.
「我…我」
"Huh... Eh...
嗚…呃…
"Er..."
嗯…
I promise that you will see me again,
我保證你會再一次見到我
in this world or another.
無論是在這個世界還是在另一個世界
"Or another."
「另一個世界」
Go on! Get in there!
進來！
"Or another."
「另一個世界」
- Hey, flyboy.     - Yeah?
-嘿，小飛俠  -嗯？
That was some little airshow you put on out there.
你搞得飛行表演倒是很厲害
Could you do that again?
你能再飛一次嗎？
Who wants to know?
誰想知道？
Of course I can fly. You saw me.
我當然能飛，你也看到了
Hmm.
嗯
Good.
很好
Put your ear to that wall over there.
把你的耳朵放到牆這裡
Now that's the sound of a blast cap I stuck to the other side.
這就是黑雷管的聲音，我把它裝到牆對面了
Set to go off in 30 seconds.
30秒後就會爆炸
If I fly, you'll help me find my mother?
如果我能飛的話，你能幫我找到我媽媽嗎？
I reckon she's here on the island.
我相信她就在這個島上
It's not a negotiation, kid.
我可沒在跟你談條件，小子
Without me, you're stuck in this cell.
要是沒有我，你就被困在這個監獄裡
Without me, you're stuck in these mines.
沒有我，你就得在這裡一直挖礦
Okay, then we'll talk about it.
好吧，我們談談
Just move away from that wall before you get yourself blown up, all right?
從牆那裡走開，否則你就會被炸成碎片，懂嗎？
- So, what's it gonna be?     - Kid!
-你同意我的條件嗎？  -臭小子！
Tick
滴
tock.
Okay, we have a deal, just...
好吧，成交，但是…
Flyboy?
小飛俠？
Hurry! Slide down.   They'll be comin' for us.
快！趴下  他們正在找我們
If I'm gonna trust you, I need to know your name.
如果我需要相信你的話，你需要告訴我你的名字
It's Hook. The name's James Hook.
虎克！  我的名字叫詹姆斯虎克
- Happy?     - No!
-高興了？  -才不！
Left foot in front of the other, put the right one in front of the other.
左腳邁到右腳前面，右腳邁到左腳前面
That's it. It's called walking.   Off you go. Go on.
很好，這叫做走路  繼續走，繼續
Smee.
史密
Well, go on, then. Carry on.
很好，繼續走
- Smee. Down here!     - Whoa.
-史密，下面！  -啥！
Six o'clock.
6點鐘方向
I don't... Yes...
我看不…看到了
Darn it, Smee, in the basket.
見鬼，史密，籃子裡
Please don't call me Smee.
請別叫我史密
Smee, can you get me to the surface?
史密，能把我拉到地面上嗎？
There is no use.
沒用的
Once you're up there, you can't get anywhere else.
你上來了以後，你也去不了別的地方
Not today.
今天未必
Good knowing ya.
認識你很高興
You've been a true friend.
你是個真朋友
Someday I'll find a way to repay you.
我總有一天會報答你的
Now, send us up.
好了，把我們拉上去
What the heck?
什麼？
You just said someday you'll find a way to repay me.
你剛才說你回頭會報答我
Someday, not today. Get out!
回頭，不是今天，上去！
I think that's a very minor technicality.
我覺得這是個小的技術問題
Someday could be today, if you think about it.
回頭也可以算今天，你仔細想想
- And, moreover...     - Smee!
-還有  -史密！
Yes.
在
That's where we're headed.
我們要往那個地方去
The Skyport.
天空碼頭
We can take one of the cable cars up to the dock.
我們可以用一個這樣的吊車到碼頭
Then you'll fly us to a ship.
然後你飛著把我們帶到船上
Okay?
行嗎？
Huh?
噢！
Keep your head down, kid.
頭低下來，小子
Go! Go!
走！
See? They anchor the galleons far enough off the dock,
看！那些大帆船已經在離碼頭足夠遠的地方拋錨了！
so they're impossible to steal.
所以我們沒法偷走他們
So you want me to fly from the dock, over to one of the...
所以你想讓我從碼頭起飛，飛躍…
What? Speak now, or forever hold your peace.
什麼？有話就說
不然就永遠保持沉默吧
Are we meant to have stopped?
我們應該在這裡停下嗎？
Heave! Heave!
用力！用力！
Forget the Skyport.   You have to do it now.
到不了天空碼頭了
現在就飛吧
Are you waiting for a formal invitation?
怎麼，你想讓我給你發個正式邀請函嗎？
- Go! Now!     - I'm afraid of heights!
-現在！  -我恐高！
What?   You can fly!
什麼？ 但是你會飛啊！
Yesterday was my first time.
我昨天第一次飛
Well, you better fly again, or we're all gonna fall for the last time.
你現在要是不飛的話，我們就全都死定了
Might we bicker about this later?
我們能不能等會兒再吵
Smee! The sword!
史密！那把劍！
Yeah, that's gonna work, kid.
你以為那就行得通，小子
Get up there and wave it at 'em.
上去，向他們揮手
Heave!
用力！
That was close.
真險
Do you know how to work a ship?
你知道怎麼開船嗎？
How hard could it be?
那能有多難
- Smee! The rope!     - Yes! Yes!
-史密，繩子！  -我知道！
- Clear!     - Boy!
-都好了！  -小子！
This is a lot harder than it looks!
這比看起來困難多了
Yeah! We're sailin' now!
哈！我們開始航行了！
Well, do you have anything to say?
你想解釋點什麼嗎？
I worked really hard setting up that table.
我很努力才把桌子搭起來
What? Forget the table.   Pick them up later.
什麼？別扯什麼桌子了
過一會兒再撿起來這些
If that boy makes it to the natives,
如果那小子到了野人那邊
you can forget any chance of us winning this war.
我們這場仗是肯定打不贏了
All will be lost.
一切都會結束的
We'll find them, sir.   They can't have gone far.
我們會找到他們的，老大
他們走不了太遠
Well, then where are they?
好吧，他們現在在什麼地方？
Get me that boy before the savages do!
在野人找到那小子之前
把他給我找到！
Dead ahead!
筆直前進！
Smee! Get off my leg!
史密！放開我的腿！
I think I'm gonna be sick!
我覺得我快要吐了！
The wall! The wall!
牆！前面是牆！
Somebody, please help me!
誰來救救我！
Turn!
轉彎！
Smee! Get the sails up!
史密！把帆升起來！
We need a strong headwind to make the jump!
我們需要很強的逆風才可以跳！
What jump?
跳？
Home! We're gettin' the heck off this island!
回家！我們需要從這個島上離開！
No-ho!
不行！
You said we'd find my mother!
你跟我保證會一起找我媽媽！
I'm not leaving Neverland!
我不會離開夢幻島！
Well, not now, anyway!
起碼現在不行！
Get the sails up!
把帆升起來！
The sails!
帆！
This is gonna be a little rough!
本次降落可能不會太平穩！
Put the sails up!
把帆升起來！
How many times...
我到底要說…
I am not to be disturbed when I'm at the Rejuvenator!
我在回春器這裡的時候不要來打擾我！
Yes?
啥事？
I am sorry, Captain, but it's about the boy.
抱歉，船長，是關於那小子的事
Mmm-hmm?
怎樣？
The stolen ship went down in the Neverwood.
被偷的船在夢幻森林那裡掉下去了
So the boy is lost?
那小子不見了？
Yes, sir. He is a lost boy.
是的，老大，那小子不見了
But our best men are searching for him now.
我們的好手都在找他
I am surrounded by imbeciles.   Must I do everything myself?
我周圍的人怎麼都是飯桶？  我難不成什麼都要自己做嗎？
Sir, you can't really believe that this pipsqueak is the one.
老大，你不可能真的相信，那個鬼扯預言是真的
He hardly seems capable.
他看起來沒有多大能耐
His mother hardly seemed capable either, and yet, here we are.
他媽媽看起來也沒什麼能耐，但是我們不還是走到這一步了
The deal was to help me find my mother.
我們說好了要幫我找我媽媽
You were gonna break it.   That's very wrong.
如果你違約的話
你這人人品有問題
No, you broke the deal first.   You lied to us.
不，是你違約在先
你對我們撒謊了
No, I fibbed. I can fly.   Just not every day.
沒有，我只是沒說清，我能飛
但不是每天都能飛
Our only way off this island
我們唯一離開這個島的方法
and now it's in pieces. Satisfied?
已經摔碎了
你滿意了？
Well, yes. I'm quite content.
對，我滿意極了
'Cause I don't wanna get off this island.
因為我一點也不想離開這個島
All the years that I've wasted planning to get out.
我這麼多年費盡心血策劃離開這裡
All gone.
全完了
Hey! Quit messing around.   It's not safe in here.
行了，都別浪費時間了
這裡不安全
Every ship has one.
所有船都有一張
A what?
什麼？
A map.
一張地圖
野人領地
What does that say?
上面說什麼？
"Tribal Territory."
「野人領地」
Exactly.
不錯
The prophecy said, "A boy would lead the tribe."
預言說：「一個男孩會帶領野人」
So what? You don't care.
那又怎樣，你又不在乎
I do. Keep going.
我在乎，繼續說
Well, Blackbeard thinks the prophecy is about me,
黑鬍子覺得預言說的是我
which means my mum is from here,
那就意味著我媽媽也從這裡來
which means the natives might know where she is.
野人會知道她在哪裡
Are you insane?
你瘋了？
Those savages would just as soon kill you as help you.
那些野人會殺了你而不是幫你
- Ever met one?     - No!
-你見過他們？  -沒有！
And I don't plan to.
我也不準備見他們
Well, they might be very nice.   I'm not afraid of 'em.
說不定他們人不錯
我不怕他們
There's a fine line between bravery and suicide, kid.
勇敢和貿然送死是有區別的，小子
I'm off to go find the Tribal Territory. Oh, goodbye!
我要去找野人領地了，再見！
He won't last an hour out there.
他在這裡活不過一小時
His problem. Not ours.
他的問題，不是我們的問題
Thing is, if he was the chosen one...
問題是，如果他就是預言之子
If that prophecy is real, trust me, he ain't it.
就算那個預言是真的
相信我，他也不是預言之子
But if they thought he was...
但是他們都覺得他是…
They believed he was...
他們覺得他是…
I bet they'd handsomely reward anyone who brought him to them.
他們肯定會給把他獻上來的人，一筆不小的獎勵
Well, they haven't got a ship.
他們又沒有船
Yeah, but they could get one.
對，但是他們能搞來一艘
Who's fought the pirates more than the natives?
除了野人，誰還和海盜打過那麼多仗？
If anyone could find a way, it's them.
如果任何人能搞到一艘船
就是他們
Just remember,
但是記住
when we find those oh-so-sweet-natured locals,
當我們找到這些和藹可親的當地人時
true or not, you tell them you're their savior.
不管真假，你就告訴他們你是傳說中的救世主
Then, we'll go our separate ways. Got it?
然後我們就各奔東西
懂了嗎？
Why would you want to leave a place like this?
你為什麼想從這個地方離開？
Where will you go?
你能去哪裡？
I don't know. Somewhere I'm a little higher up
我不知道
一個我能在食物鏈更靠上一點地方
on the food chain, for starters.
比如說
What was that?
那是什麼？
Somethin' a little higher up on the food chain.
食物鏈更靠上一點的地方
Oh, that is pretty, Hook.   Do you see that?
看那些漂亮的東西，虎克
你看到了嗎？
We got pirates tryin' to shoot us down with cannons.
這裡有很多海盜想用大炮把我們打下來
Nearly falling a thousand feet to our deaths.
這次差點從300多米高空摔下來
Twice. Shipwrecked.
2次，上一次船掉下來了
And you see something like that and you think to yourself,
你看到這些東西，你就會覺得…
"Oh, worth it."
「值得」
Are you an orphan?
你是孤兒嗎？
My ma left me. That count?
我媽拋棄了我，這算麼？
Well, do you remember her?
你還記得她？
I'm not wasting tears missing someone who never missed me.
我不會在不關心我的人身上浪費眼淚的
Maybe she does.
她有可能是關心你的
How can you know?
你怎麼知道？
Do you really believe your mum's here?
你真的覺得你媽媽就在這裡？
Well, she left me a note saying...
她留給我了一張紙條說…
Oh, well, if she left you a note, sure.
她給你留了一張條子就肯定沒錯了
Just 'cause yours never loved you...
就算是你媽媽從沒愛過你
Stop.
停
...doesn't mean my mum never loved me.
並不代表我媽媽從沒愛過我
Stop talking right now.
立馬閉嘴
Did you hear that?
你聽到了嗎？
It was a deafening nightmare shriek.
是震耳欲聾的、噩夢般的尖叫
- How can anyone not have heard...     - Shh.
-怎麼可能沒人聽見…  -噓
That's a Neverbird.
是夢幻鳥
And so is that.
就是它
What're we gonna do?
我們該怎麼做？
We need a plan. We need a plan!
我們需要一個計劃，我們需要一個計劃！
Run!
逃！
We'll lose them in the mist!   Go!
它們沒法在濃霧裡抓到我們！ 快跑！
Go!
快！
Run, Smee!
快跑，史密！
Their faces are terrible, but their feathers are quite lovely.
它們臉長得可真醜，但是羽毛倒是挺漂亮的
Shut up and run!
閉嘴快跑！
Go!
快！
Smee!
史密！
Peter!
彼得！
Hook? Is that you?
虎克？是你嗎？
Peter.
彼得
Hook, they've got Smee.
虎克，它們把史密抓走了
No.
不會的
Don't worry.   Everything's gonna be all right!
別擔心，一切都…會沒事的！
I knew we'd find the natives.
我知道我們會找到野人的
We're saved.
我們安全了
Please! I'm ready to go home now, please.
求你，我想回家了，求求你
Let me handle this.
讓我來處理
Good fair lady. We come in peace.
美麗的女士
我們沒有惡意
And with treasure.
來帶來了寶物
May I proudly present to you...
請讓我為您獻上…
Pan!
潘！
Pan! Pan!
潘！潘！
Pan!
潘！
Pan! Pan!
潘！潘！
Pan!
潘！
Smee!
史密！
- Smee!     - What?
-史密！  -什麼？
What are they singing about?
他們在唱什麼？
Search me!
不知道
Pan! Pan!
潘！潘！
What's going on? What's "Pan"?
發生了什麼？「潘」是什麼？
The Pan is our tribe's bravest warrior.
潘是我們部落最勇敢的武士
It's our tradition to grant you the chance to win
我們的習俗是給你贏得自由的機會
your freedom before we kill you and your friends.
在我們殺掉你和你朋友之前
Kill? What do you mean, "kill"?
殺掉？什麼叫「殺掉」？
You are our sworn enemy. You're pirates.
你是我們的敵人
你們是海盜
Pirates? We're not pirates. Hold on!
海盜？  我們不是海盜，等等！
The kid is the one you've been waiting for.
這個孩子就是你們等的人
Listen!
聽我講！
Your chance to live,
你唯一活下來的機會
your fiercest fighter against ours. Our Pan.
就是讓你那邊最勇猛的勇士來和我們的潘戰鬥
You win, you live.
你贏了，就可以走
- You lose...     - I get the idea.
-你輸了的話…  -我懂了
Huh?
蛤？
Bye for now.
你請吧
Pan!
潘！
So how do we know when to start?
我們怎麼知道決鬥什麼時候開始？
- Smee!     - What?
-史密！  -怎麼？
We have to tell them about my mother.
我們需要把我媽媽的事情和他們講講
No one cares about your darn mother!
沒人管你什麼媽媽！
Sorry, that was a bit harsh.
抱歉，我話說重了
Okay.
好吧
Your Highness.
殿下
I was hoping to get you alone.
我想和您私下聊聊
Stop!
停！
The little one.
小傢伙
He wears the Pan.
他帶著「潘吊墜」
He's a boy that can fly.
他就是那個能飛的男孩
I've seen it. It's terrific.
我見過，很厲害
We call this the Memory Tree.
這是記憶之樹
It was a time of war.
那是一段戰火瀰漫的日子
Blackbeard destroyed everything in pursuit of the Pixum.
黑鬍子為了拿到精靈粉，毀掉了所有擋住他的事物
But then, the chief made a pact with the great fairy king,
就在那時，酋長和精靈王達成協議，結為聯盟
uniting our peoples against the pirates.
共同抵抗海盜
One night, the king's son, the fairy prince,
有一天晚上，精靈王子
found his way onto Blackbeard's ship.
潛入了黑鬍子的戰船
Her name was Mary, the love of Blackbeard's life
她的名字是瑪麗，黑鬍子一生最愛的人
and his most prized possession.
他最珍貴的寶物
Night after night, the prince visited Mary.
每天晚上，精靈王子都去找瑪麗
But when Blackbeard discovered them, he flew into a jealous rage.
當黑鬍子發現了他們的感情，他的理智被嫉妒摧毀
So in order to save her, the prince took human form.
為了救她，精靈王子化身為人
But though fairies can live many thousands of years,
雖然精靈生命有幾千年
in human flesh, they can live only one day.
但是化身為人就只能存活一天
The prince sacrificed his life for the girl he loved.
精靈王子為了他愛的姑娘獻出了生命
And the child of that love...
這個愛情的結晶…
was you.
就是你
Our people helped your mother hide you in the other world.
我們的族人幫助你母親把你藏在另一個世界
And they made you this totem,
他們給你做了這個圖騰項鏈
so that when you returned, we would know it was you.
這樣你回來的時候
我們就認得出你了
What happened to my mother?
我媽媽怎麼樣了？
She returned to the Neverwood and fought for us many years.
她回了夢幻森林
成為了我們勇士中的一員
And?
然後呢？
The pirates were winning the war,
海盜們節節勝利
and the fairies had to retreat to a hidden kingdom.
精靈們不得不撤退到地下世界
They've remained there, in hiding,
他們一直藏匿在地下
unknown by Blackbeard until a time when they can reemerge and fight.
黑鬍子也找不到他們，直到他們可以重新戰鬥的那一天
And my mother?
我媽媽呢？
- She's with them.     - She's alive?
-她和他們在一起  -她還活著？
Are you sure? I have to go to her!
你確定？我要去找她！
- Please, take me now!     - No.
-求求你，帶我去  -不行
You must be patient.
你必須要有耐心
But she's waiting for me.
但她正在等我
The fairy kingdom is the greatest secret of this land.
精靈王國是這片土地上最大的秘密
Our duty is to protect it.
我們的責任就是保護它
Before we take you there,
在我帶你去之前
you must prove yourself to be Mary's son.
你必須證明你是瑪麗的兒子
The one we've been waiting for.
我們一直等待的人
When the third moon rises,
當月亮第三次升起
he must fly.
他必須能飛起來
If he lives, he's the one.
如果他能平安回來，他就是預言之子
One second.
等一下
And if he dies?
如果他死了呢？
He's an imposter.
他就是個假貨
His death will be justified.
他死得其所
Three days!
三天！
I've got the necklace.   Isn't that enough?
我已經有項鏈了
這還不夠麼？
You could've stolen it.
你有可能是偷的
But I didn't. Tell her!
我沒有！告訴她！
Kid's always had that thing.
這孩子一直有這東西
How long have you known him?
你認識他多久了？
- Three days.     - All my life.
-三天  -從出生就認識
The flying thing is a stupid detail.
要證明會飛
這事實在是太愚蠢了
Why can't they just see that?
他們不這麼覺得嗎？
If you don't believe, Peter, then neither will they.
如果你自己都不相信自己，彼得，他們也不會相信你的
But if you do, they will, too.   I promise.
如果你相信，他們也會相信的  我保證
Are you who they think you are?
你真的是他們想找的那個人嗎？
- I don't know.     - Hey.
-我不知道  -嘿
They think you're their messiah,
他們覺得你是他們的救世主
that you're here to liberate them.
你會來解放他們
Are they right?
對嗎？
I said, I don't know!
我說了，我不知道！
Rabbits.
小兔兔…
I believe.
我相信
I can fly!
我能飛！
If only Nibs was here.
要是尼布斯在這裡就好了
He'd know how to help.
他會幫我想法子
I believe.
我相信
Have you seen Smee?
你見到史密了嗎？
These things they expect me to do,
他們想讓我做的這些事
I can't do them, Hook.   I've tried.
虎克，我做不了  我試過了
- Hey. Stop. Hey!     - I can't do the things,
-嘿，停！  -我做不了這些事
so I can't be the one!
我不是他們要的那個人！
Listen.
聽我講
Hook, what the bloody hell am I?
虎克，我到底是什麼？
You can go feeling sorry for yourself all you want, kid.
你可以自憐自哀，小子
But knowing where you're from,
但是知道你的來歷
that's half of knowing who you are.
就已經一半知道了你是什麼樣的人
That's more than most of us here will ever know.
我們大多數人最多也只瞭解這麼多
But you said that your mother left you.
但是你說你母親拋棄了你
Yeah. I lied. I do that sometimes.
我騙你的
我有時候會撒謊
It's called being a grown-up!
這是成人世界的一部分
Least you know where you come from.
至少你知道你是從哪裡來的
Born to a warrior, heir to a prince.
天生就是勇者
一個王子
Does that mean you're the one?   I don't know.
這就證明你是命運之子嗎？  我不知道
I don't know if there is a "one."
我不知道有沒有所謂的「命運之子」
But I do know
但是我知道
that if you aren't the guy,
如果你不是那個人
and you are just you,
你就是你
maybe that's enough.
那就足夠了
Where's the boy?
那小子在哪裡？
Spill the beans, or I'll spill your blood.
告訴我真話，否則我就殺了你
I'll never tell.
我不會說的
He's right over there.
他就在那裡
Nope, nope. Wait, my mistake.
不，等一下，我說錯了
Pretty sure it's that way. No!
肯定是那個方向，不！
No. Right the first time.
不！第一次是對的
Definitely, maybe definitely, this way.
絕對，可能絕對
是這個方向
The point is, we're very close.
我的意思是
我們離他很近
Ready the ships. Bishop, kill him.
準備好戰船
畢世坡，殺了他
No! Just wait!
別，等一下！
Wait!
等等！
You might not wanna kill me just yet.
你可能現在還不想殺我
For I hold the crown jewels, you know.
我知道很值錢的秘密
- Informationally.     - Speak.
-秘密  -說吧
Sorry, a bit nervous.   You are quite intimidating.
不好意思我有點緊張
你有點嚇人
Speak!
說吧！
Now, you know the so-called extinct fairy kingdom, hmm?
你聽說過所謂滅絕了的精靈王國嗎？
Speak.
講
Sorry.
抱歉
I was just lookin' for you.
我剛剛正在找你
Well, you found me.
你現在已經找到我了
Don't see things like that in the mines.
我在礦山裡可看不到這些
Kinda beautiful.
真美
So, do you like sunrises?
你喜歡日出？
What is it you think you're doing?
你覺得你在做什麼？
Well, I think it's called flirting,
應該叫調情
but if you have to ask, I might be doin' it wrong.
如果你問的話
我可能沒調好
You're not like the men from my tribe.
你和我族群裡面的男人不太一樣
Thank you.
謝謝
No, they're honest.
不，他們講實話
- Strong. Brave.     - Brave.
-強壯，勇敢  -勇敢
That what you call it?
你真的這麼覺得？
Letting my little buddy take a leap to his death.
讓一個小男孩做這樣必死的舉動
When he ceases to doubt himself, he will fly.
當他不再懷疑自己的時候，他就可以飛起來
How do we know there are any fairies still left on this island...
我們怎麼知道還有沒有精靈，存留在這塊土地上
or that they'll come help fight just 'cause they see him fly?
或是願意幫助我們打仗，就因為他們看到了能飛的男孩？
You have to trust us.
你要相信我們
Why should we?   You certainly don't trust us.
我們為什麼要相信你們？  你們又不相信我們
There's a map to the fairy kingdom.
有一張通往精靈王國地圖
We guard it with our lives.
是我們誓死扞衛的
Of course there is.
行，有張地圖
Why wouldn't there be a secret map to the secret kingdom?
為什麼這個秘密王國不能有個秘密地圖？
This isn't a game.
我沒在和你玩遊戲
You've seen what Blackbeard has done to Neverland already.
你已經見到了黑鬍子對夢幻島做的一切
He'll reduce the rest of it to nothing but mine pits if we don't stop him.
如果我們不阻止他的話，他會把一切化為齏粉
Has anybody ever told you, you have really beautiful eyes?
有沒有人說過你的眼睛很漂亮？
Fire on the foredeck, prepare to come around.
甲板上架好武器，準備掉頭
Tiger Lily!
虎蓮！
You missed.
你沒擊中我
We must find Peter!
我們必須找到彼得！
Shoot her!
朝他射擊！
- Peter!     - Where's Hook?
-彼得！  -虎克在哪裡？
All of this because of you.
這一切都是你造成的
No, Kwahu, wait!
不要，凱虎，等等
You're welcome. Now, come on.
不用客氣，走吧
Keep moving!
繼續走！
Well, well, well.
哎呦
The princess, I presume.
我猜是公主殿下
Oh, well, actually, I'm just a miner,
我只是個礦工
but I appreciate the compliment.
但是多謝你的誇讚
Bishop.
畢世坡
Go on.
快走
Line them up.
讓他們站成一排
Down here.
這邊
All these years digging our hands raw
這麼多年拼了老命挖礦
for tiny lumps of Pixum,
就為了那一點精靈粉
and now I learn from Mr. Smee...
現在我從史密先生處得知
you know where there's a mountain of the stuff.
這裡堆成山的精靈粉在哪裡
Nice as pie.
很簡單
Tell me where the boy is...
告訴我男孩在哪裡
and how to find the fairy kingdom, and you may live.
還有精靈王國在什麼地方，你就能活著離開
Death is the greatest adventure.
死亡是最刺激的旅行
Bon voyage.
一路順風
All hail the new Chiefette.
新酋長萬歲！
Princess Tiger Lily.
虎蓮公主
All hail!
萬歲！
Tell him. He'll kill you.
告訴他，否則他會殺了你的
He's right, you know.
他說的一點沒錯
Nice birdie.
乖鳥兒
- There's a map.     - Traitor.
-有一張地圖  -叛徒
Don't shoot her.   She told me there's a map to the fairy kingdom.
別殺她！  她告訴過我有一張去精靈王國的地圖
Traitor! How dare you betray us, pirate?
叛徒！你竟敢背叛我們？
I'm trying to save your lives, sweetheart.
甜心，我在想救你一命
It won't happen again.
下次不會了
Oh, it won't, I guarantee it.
不會了，我保證
Captain.
船長
Go, kid.
小子，來吧
Yeah!
哇
Kill them all!
殺了他們！
Attack. Attack!
開火！
No!
不要！
Can I tell you something, Peter?
彼得，我要告訴你
You'll never find your mother.
你永遠找不到你媽媽
Yes, I will find her.
我會找到她的
No, you really, really won't.
不，你永遠不會
You'll never find your mother.   Do you know why?
你永遠找不到你媽媽
你知道為什麼嗎？
Because I killed her.
因為我殺了她
She died at my hand. By this very blade.
她死在我手中這把劍下
As you will, too.
你也會是同樣的下場
Close your eyes, Peter, and think a happy thought.
閉上眼，彼得
想點開心的事
Bad form, sir!
先生，你可真是無禮
We have to run, now!
我們快跑！
No. We have to jump.
不，我們要跳下去
Peter, are you hurt?
彼得，你受傷了嗎？
Well, I'm fine, too. Thanks for asking.
我也沒事
謝謝你的關心
Don't speak to me.
別跟我說話
Because of you, everything my people have fought to protect
就是因為你
我們所有扞衛的東西…
- will be destroyed.     - Hey...
-都會被毀滅  -嘿
Because of you, the Chief is dead.
都是因為你，酋長死了
- Smee was the rat.     - He was your friend.
-史密才是叛徒  -但他是你的朋友
- How was I supposed to know?     - You should've known.
-我怎麼會知道  -你應該知道的
- I'm sorry.     - You should've known.
-我很抱歉  -你應該知道的
I'm sorry if I did something wrong!
如果我做錯了什麼我很抱歉
Where's Peter?
彼得去哪裡了？
Peter.
彼得
You lied.
你騙人
- You all lied.     - I'm sorry.
-你全是騙人  -我很抱歉
So, it's true?
他說的是真的嗎？
It's complicated.
這很複雜
Is my mother alive or isn't she?
我媽媽到底是還活著還是已經死了？
Blackbeard spoke the truth.
黑鬍子說的是實話
And you lied to me.
那你就是騙了我
Had we told you she was dead, you'd have walked away from your destiny.
如果我們告訴你她死了，你就會放棄你的使命
Whoever it is you think I am,
不管你覺得我是誰
whatever it is you expect me to be,
不管你覺得我應該變成誰
I'm not.
我不是
And I can't.
我也不能
I couldn't...
我也辦不到…
I didn't wanna watch you die.
我不想看著你死
You should've closed your eyes.
你應該閉上眼睛的
Blackbeard won't stop searching for Peter.
黑鬍子不會停止尋找彼得的
There's only one place on this island he wouldn't dare look.
這個島上只有一個地方他不敢去查
Mermaid Lagoon? Sounds pretty.
人魚湖？ 聽起來不錯
So pirates are afraid of mermaids?
海盜害怕人魚？
Because of what we will pass through to get there.
因為那些我們也要經歷的危險
Yeah?
例如？
Crocodiles.
鱷魚
Afraid?
害怕了？
No, ma'am.
不，女士
Find the map. Keep looking.
繼續找那張地圖
Does Smee please thee?
您對史密滿意了嗎？
Pull the place apart!
給我掘地三尺地找！
- So may Smee be free?     - No, you're too useful.
-史密能走了嗎？  -不行，你太有用了
But Smee was promised...
但是您答應了史密
Smee should cease to talk of himself in the third person,
如果史密再自己用第三人稱稱呼自己的話
- or Smee will be a non-person.     - Yes.
-史密就可以消失了  -我懂了
I found it.
找到了
It's a map to the fairy kingdom.
這就是通往精靈王國的地圖
Ready the ships!
準備戰船！
We must get there before Peter.
我們必須在彼得之前趕到那裡
直到永遠
Grab the torches.   They're afraid of the light.
拿上火把
他們怕光
Did we scare 'em off?
我們把他們嚇跑了？
Oh, come on. They can fly?
拜託，他們會飛嗎？
Keep waving the torches.
繼續揮動火把
There!
那裡！
Peter!
彼得！
I think I see him.
我找到他了
Where?
哪裡？
- Reach for my hand!     - Help! Help!
-抓住我的手！  -救命！
Peter.
彼得
What happened?
發生了什麼？
What the heck are those?
那些是什麼？
I don't know, but I think you're gonna like 'em.
我不知道
但我覺得你可能不會喜歡這些東西
You could say that again.
說得不錯
Hey, hey, hey. Don't go.
等等，別走
- I'm gonna check it out.     - Be careful.
-我去看看  -小心
Who's more careful than me?
誰能比我更小心呢？
I'm sorry I didn't tell you what happened to your mother.
很抱歉，我沒把你媽媽的事情告訴你
But Blackbeard didn't tell you the whole truth either.
但是黑鬍子也沒把所有真相告訴你
Let me show you.
跟我來
The mermaids charged these waters with memories.
人魚把這些水中注滿了回憶
You can see the past.
你可以看到過去
Deep breath.
深呼吸
There's no time.
沒時間了
Blackbeard's men nearly have us.
黑鬍子的人差點抓到了我們
Go to the fairy kingdom. Hide.   Keep our people safe.
去精靈王國藏起來
保護我們的人民
You should never have come back, Mary.
你不應該回來的，瑪麗
And yet, here you are.
但是你還是回來了
Ready to die for them rather than live with me.
你寧願為了他們死也不願意和我生活在一起
No. Mary.
不，瑪麗
No! No.
不
No!
不！
She was a warrior.
她是個勇士
A great warrior.   Her sacrifice still inspires us.
一個出色的勇士
她的犧牲會激勵我們
Did you know her?
你認識她？
She trained me.
她是我的導師
Would she have been proud of me?
她會為我驕傲嗎？
Yes.
會的
Very.
非常驕傲
But what if I can't do what she did?
如果我做不了她曾經做的呢？
What if I fail to fulfill the prophecy?
如果無法履行預言呢？
And what if you fail to try, Peter?
如果你不努力呢，彼得？
What are you then?
那又會怎樣？
Hey!
嗨！
You've gotta see this.
你們來看這個
Now, the hull's a little banged up.
船體有些破損了
And see those teeth marks?   Boy, those crocs can jump.
看到這些牙印了嗎？  這些鱷魚是可以跳很高的
But once I get her fixed up, she's gonna be in good shape.
但是把她修好後
又是條好船
For what?
為什麼？
To get us the hell off this island.
我們就可以離開這個島
You're going to run like a coward?
你只是想像懦夫一樣逃跑？
Well, I never really thought of it in those exact terms,
我不會這麼說
but, generally speaking, yes.
但是你的意思也沒錯
And where will you go?
你去哪裡？
Home. It's, you know,
回家，你知道
where I come from.
回我來的地方
Home's not where you come from.   It's where you make it.
家不是你來的地方，而是你創造的地方
So help me do that.
那你幫我做一個那樣的家好了
Anyone that survived Blackbeard's attack is in the mine by now.
所有被黑鬍子襲擊的生還者都在礦山
And I've been there, and I'm not going back.
我也在那裡過
我可不想回去
Not for anything or anyone.
什麼東西或人都不能讓我回去
Well, if you have no reason to stay, then go.
如果你沒有留下的原因的話，你走好了
Go now. Leave us to die.
走吧，讓我們在這裡等死
I don't want you to die.
我不想讓你死
I want you to come with me.
我想讓你和我一起走
And if I don't?
如果我不願意呢？
Then that's your decision. Not mine.
那是你的決定，不是我的
Well, kid.
小子
Looks like the old gang's back together.
看來我們又聚到一起了
Let's get this ship in the air.
我們試著讓這個船升空
Let's get one thing straight.
我有一件事要跟你說明白
I'm not the chosen one,
我不是命運之子
and the prophecy wasn't about me if it was ever real at all.
預言也不是關於我的，預言也不一定是真的
But I am my mother's son.
但是我是我媽媽的兒子
And if Blackbeard is going to destroy everything my parents died for,
如果黑鬍子要毀掉我父母誓死扞衛的東西
I'll stand against him to the last.   Just like they did.
我會和他戰鬥到底
就像我的父母一樣
Now,
現在
take me to the fairy kingdom.
帶我去精靈王國吧
It's just as the Chief described it.
就像酋長所說的
These are words.
這些文字
- What language is it?     - Must be fairy.
-這是什麼語言？  -一定是精靈語
I can read.
我會讀
I can read it.
我認得這些
What does it say?
它說什麼？
"Only the prince who bears the key shall pass."
「只有手持鑰匙的王子才可以通過」
Just that.
就這樣？
Then some boring stuff about the great fallen dead.
還有一些無聊的關於戰死勇士的事
It means we need a key.
所以我們需要一把鑰匙
Then this was all for nothing.
否則一切都白搭
No, I wouldn't say that.
未必
"The prince who bears the key."
「持有鑰匙的王子」
Don't you see, Peter?
你不懂嗎？彼得
- I am the...     - You bear the key.
-我就是…  -你就有鑰匙
I do?
我有？
You've had it all along.
你一直都有
- She knew I'd come for her.     - Yes.
-她知道我會來找她的  -不錯
Mum tries to protect the kingdom by giving son the key.
她為了保護這個國家
把鑰匙給了她兒子
I kill Mum, but fail to kill the son.
我殺了媽媽，但是沒殺死孩子
In turn, son fails to protect the kingdom by giving me the key.
所以，兒子為了保護這個國家就需要把鑰匙給我
Mum would be very disappointed.
媽媽可是會很失望的
Wouldn't she?
不是嗎？
Eternity beckons.
永生近在咫尺
I will live forever.
我將長生不老
Wakey, wakey! Rise and shine!
起床了！都日上三竿了！
That's where we're going.
那就是我們的目的地
The fairy hive.
精靈堡
Destroy that, and we destroy them all.
毀了那個東西，就能毀滅他們所有人
Yes!
不錯！
Yes! Oh! Come!
來吧！
Come on. Come.
快快快
Yes.
來了
Her name's Tinkerbell.
她的名字叫小叮噹
I can hear her.
我能聽到她
They've been waiting for you, Peter.
他們一直在等你，彼得
You have to get away from here!
你必須要離開這裡
He's going to destroy you all.
他會毀了你們的
I know what I was meant to do, but I failed.
我知道我的任務是什麼
但是我失敗了
I'm sorry.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry!
All right, boys, let's burn them!
來吧兄弟們，把他們燒乾淨！
Burn them!
燒掉他們！
Burn them, burn them, burn them!
- Burn them all!     - No!
-全部燒乾淨！  -不要！
Please, I'll do anything!
求你，我什麼都可以做！
- Please!     - Oh, don't beg.
-求你！  -不用求我
Anything.
什麼都可以
No. It's bad form to beg.
別這樣，求人是很難堪的
Where's your sense of honor, boy?
你怎麼一點榮譽感都沒有？
Now, kneel.
跪下
I said kneel!
我說跪下！
I am the son of a warrior and a prince.
我是勇士之子，一個王子
I will never bow to you.
我是不會向你屈服的
If you're gonna kill me, then get on with it.
你要是想殺我就殺吧
As you wish.
既然你是這麼希望的
You don't have to do this.
不要殺他
No.
想得美
But I really want to.
我可是很想殺了他
Did you miss me?
想我了嗎？
Why is it always him?
怎麼總是你？
Jump!
跳！
You came back!   I thought you didn't care!
你回來了！我以為你不在乎我！
Like I said, sometimes I lie.
就像我以前說的，我有時候會撒謊
Come on!
快點！
I can't let Blackbeard get to the hive!
我不能讓黑鬍子去精靈堡！
Hard to port!
快往左轉！
Mind if I cut in?
我能插句話嗎？
We've gotta help her!
我們需要幫她！
Take the wheel!
攥住方向盤！
You're gonna get this puppy as close to them as you can.
我們需要靠得越近越好！
- Okay!     - And I'll jump across!
-好吧！  -我會跳過去！
Hold on!
當心！
Captain!
船長！
No.
不
Peter, no!
彼得，不！
No.
不
It's over, boy.
都結束了，小子
Come.
過來
You! Grab that girl!
你！抓住那個女孩！
Pan!
潘！
I can fly!
我能飛了！
Look at me, Hook, I'm flying!
看著我，虎克，我能飛了！
All right, you don't have to crow about it.
行了，別吵了
Crow all you want! Just don't drop me!
你隨便吵吧，別丟下我就行！
Go on.
去吧
If we're gonna beat him,
如果我們想打敗他
we're gonna do it together.
就必須聯手
Do you hear me?
懂了嗎？
Good!
很好
Now, come on, then.
過來
Fire!
開火！
Ready?
準備好了？
Go!
來吧！
Got you!
抓到你了！
Think a happy thought.
想點開心事
No!
不要！
Boy!
小子！
□ Hello
Peter.
彼得
Mum?
媽媽？
You found me.
你找到我了
I have your eyes.
我的眼睛和你的很像
You have my heart.
你的心和我也很像
I've imagined this moment my whole life, and now...
我想像了很多次這一刻，現在…
I love you, Mum. So much.
我很愛你，媽媽
I don't know how you can miss someone you've never met,
我不知道怎麼可以關心一個從沒見過的人
but I've missed you every day.
但是我每天都很想你
Every day?
每天？
Without you, I'm lost again.   What do I do now?
沒有你，我就會迷路
我現在該做什麼？
You're not lost.
你沒有迷路
You are home.
你已經回家了
On this island, with these people.
在這個島上，和大家在一起
Your people.
你的人民
Your family.
你的家人
You must never give up on them,
你不能放棄他們
as you never gave up on me.
就像你從未放棄過我一樣
But, Mum,
但是媽媽
I don't want to lose you again.
我不想再一次失去你
You'll never lose me.
你永遠不會失去我
I'll always be part of this Neverland.
我是這夢幻島的一部分
And a part of you.
也是你的一部分
I love you, my son.
孩子，我愛你
My Peter.
我的彼得
My Peter Pan.
我的彼得潘
Peter.
彼得
Peter?
彼得？
You thought I'd leave you here.
你以為我會丟下你在這裡？
- No, I never.     - Feel like some fun?
-你不會那樣做的  -想做點刺激的事情嗎？
Yes, please.
當然
All right, gentlemen.
先生們
- Hold on tight.     - Peter!
-抓緊了  -彼得！
You don't have a rope.
你沒有一根繩子
We have a lot to talk about.
我有很多事情要告訴你
I thought you were leaving.
我以為你走了
Change of heart.
我改變主意了
Will you take the wheel, please?
你能抓住方向盤嗎？
You don't want to go home?
你不想回家了？
I already am.
我已經到家了
Is he a pirate, too?
他也是海盜嗎？
No.
不是
Not yet, anyway.
起碼現在還不是
Which way shall we go?
我們往哪裡走？
- Set a course!     - Set a course!
-定個路線！  -定個路線！
Hey, who's in charge here?
這裡誰管事？
Well, I'm the captain.
我是船長
And I'm the chosen one.
我還是命運之子呢
We'll have plenty of time to argue about that later, flyboy.
我們有的是時間爭論這些，小飛俠
Suit yourself, Captain Hook.
請便，虎克船長
Set a course.
定好方向
Second to the right and straight on till morning.
向右轉，沿著那個方向一直走到早上
Neverland!
夢幻島！
骷髏旗
We'll always be friends, Hook. Won't we?
虎克，我們永遠都是朋友，對不對？
Always.   What could possibly go wrong?
對的！ 還能有什麼糟糕事情發生？
導演
喬 萊特
編劇
傑森 法區
原著童話
詹姆斯 馬修 巴利
休 傑克曼
蓋瑞特 荷德倫
魯妮 瑪拉
特別介紹　萊維 米勒
小飛俠
幻夢啟航
感感感感感感感感感感感感感感感感感
感感感感　　感感感感感　　感感感感
感感　感　感感感感感感　感感感感感
感感　感　感感感　　　　　　　感感
感感　　　　　感感感感　感感感感感
感　感感　感感感感感感　感感感感感
感　感感　感感　　　　　　　　　感
感感感感　感　感感感感感　感感感感
感感感感　　感感感感感感　感　感感
感感感　　感感　　　　　　　　　感
感　　　　感感感感感感感　感感感感
感感　感　感感　感感感感　感感感感
感感感感　感感感　　感感　感感感感
感感感感　感感感感感感感　感感感感
感感感感　感感感感感　　　感感感感
感感感感　感感感感感感　感感感感感
感感感感感感感感感感感感感感感感感
hey5377880@pchome.com.tw
謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝
謝謝謝謝　　謝謝謝謝　　謝謝謝謝謝
謝謝謝謝　謝謝　謝謝　謝謝謝謝謝謝
謝　　　　　　　　謝　謝謝謝　謝謝
謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝　　　　　　謝
謝謝　　謝謝　謝謝謝　謝謝謝　謝謝
謝謝　謝謝謝謝　謝謝　謝謝謝　謝謝
謝謝　謝謝　謝　謝　謝　謝謝　謝謝
謝　謝　謝　謝謝謝　謝　謝　謝謝謝
謝謝謝　謝　謝謝　謝謝　謝　謝謝謝
謝謝謝謝　謝謝謝謝謝謝謝　謝謝謝謝
謝謝謝　謝　謝謝謝謝謝謝　謝謝謝謝
謝謝謝　謝謝　謝謝謝謝　謝　謝謝謝
謝謝　謝謝謝　謝謝謝謝　謝謝　謝謝
謝　謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝　謝謝謝　謝謝
謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝　　謝謝謝謝謝　謝
謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝
hey5377880@pchome.com.tw
收收收收收收收收收收收收收收收收收
收收收收收收收收　　收收收收收收收
收收收收收收收收　收收收收　收收收
收收收收收收收收　　　　　　　收收
收收收收收收收收　收收收收收收收收
收收收　　　　　　　　　　　收收收
收收收　收收收收收收收收收　收收收
收收收收收收收收　收收收收收收收收
收收收收收收收收　收收收收收　收收
收　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　收
收收收收收收收收　收收收收收收收收
收收收收收收收收收收收收收收收收收
hey5377880@pchome.com.tw
看看看看看看看看看看看看看看看看看
看看看看看　看看看看看　看看看看看
看　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　看
看看看看看看看　看看看看看看看看看
看看看　　　　　　　　看看　　看看
看看看看看看看　看看看看　　看看看
看看看看看看看　看看看　看看看看看
看　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　看
看看看看看看看看　看　看看看看看看
看看看看看看　　看看看　看看看看看
看看看　　　　　　　　　　看看看看
看　　看看　看看看看看看　看看看看
看看看看看　　　　　　　　看看看看
看看看看看　看看看看看看　看看看看
看看看看看看看看看看看看看看看看看
hey5377880@pchome.com.tw
僅以此片獻給祖班、莫翰和奧辛，並紀念丹尼舒克特
小飛俠
幻夢啟航